Guide to the Virtual Library of Virginia records, 1994-2004
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Committees, April 1994-September 2004; (13 boxes)
  - Subseries 1.4: VIVA Outreach Committee, October 1996-July 2001
    - Committee Annual Reports, July 1999-June 2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      1999-2000 Annual reports from the Outreach Committee, the Resource Sharing Committee and the Resources for Users Committee.
  - Subseries 1.5: VIVA Special Collections Committee, June 1995-January 2003
    This subseries contains material generated by the Special Collections Committee. The Special Collections Committee files includes correspondence, exhibition programs, a press release, contact lists, information about the Virginia Heritage Project and EAD workshop participant lists and reimbursement information.
    - VIVA-Special Collections Committee, June 1995-June 1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Information and correspondence from the Special Collections Committee including contact lists, digital training workshop information package, meeting minutes, program for "'Twas The Night Before Christmas" exhibition, press release about the Electronic Archive of Early American Fiction, a draft proposal and description of the Virginia Heritage Collection Project, and a TechBooks publication.
    - VIVA-Special Collections-Virginia Heritage Project, August 2000-January 2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Information and correspondence from the Special Collections Committee about the Virginia Heritage Project. Documents include Virginia Heritage Project executive committee meeting minutes and agendas, budget information, grant proposals, a Virginia Heritage Project description and a committee list.
    - Special Collections Committee-Workshops, January-February 1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Information regarding reimbursement information and participant list for the January 1999 EAD workshop.
  - Subseries 1.6: VIVA Technical Issues Committee, April 1994-January 1999
    This subseries contains material generated by the Technical Issues committee. Documents include correspondence, meeting notes, agendas, and minutes, VIVA institutional information, budget information, committee and member lists, as well as information about the User Authentication Workshop.
    - Technical Issues Committee, April 1994-September 1997 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Information and correspondence from the Technical Issues committee. Materials include meeting notes, agendas and minutes, VIVA fact sheets, member lists, VIVA institutional IP addresses, budget information, equipment surveys and institutional subscription information.
    - Technical Issues Committee-User Authentication Workshop, December 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Information and correspondence from the December 1997 User Authentication Workshop. Materials include workshop agendas, notes, registration workshop, logistical information, a VIVA information packet and workshop surveys.
    - Technical Issues Committee, January 1998-January 1999 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Information and correspondence from the Technical Issues committee. Materials include meeting agendas and minutes.
- Series 2: VIVA Events and Meetings, January 1995-August 2001; (3 boxes)
  This series contains material generated by the various meetings, forums, training sessions and workshops held throughout Virginia and organized by and for VIVA. The series is made up of two subseries, the first contains documents from the official VIVA regional meetings, and the second contains material generated by VIVA training sessions, forums, and workshops.
  - Subseries 2.1: Regional Meetings, January-July 1995
    This subseries contains material generated by a series of regional VIVA meetings held throughout Virginia between April 4 and April 7, 1995. Material includes meeting agendas, minutes and notes, attendance lists, contact lists, logistical information, evaluations, information about software and computer programs and fact sheets.
    - Regional Meeting at Virginia Polytechnic Institute, April 4, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Documents produced for the April 4, 1995 regional meeting at Virginia Tech. Materials include meeting agendas and attendance lists.
    - Regional Meeting at Christopher Newport University, April 5, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Documents produced for the April 5, 1995 regional meeting at Christopher Newport University. Materials include meeting agendas, individual attendance lists, and attendance lists by institution.
    - Regional Meeting at The University of Richmond, April 6, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Documents produced for the April 6, 1995 regional meeting at The University of Richmond. Materials include meeting agendas and attendance lists.
    - Regional Meeting at George Mason University, April 7, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Documents produced for the April 7, 1995 regional meeting at George Mason University. Materials include meeting agendas, individual attendance lists, meeting logistical information, correspondence and user services training session evaluations.
    - ILL Regional Meetings I, January-April 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Documents and correspondence from interlibrary loan regional meetings throughout Virginia. Materials include meeting agendas and notes, contact lists, a draft VIVA brochure, presentation slides, Ariel information, workshop information and logistical paperwork, budget information and fact sheets.
    - ILL Regional Meetings II, April-July 1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Documents and correspondence from interlibrary loan regional meetings. Materials include VIVA fact sheets, presentation slides outline, overhead transparencies, attendance lists, Ariel information, contact lists, meeting agendas and minutes as well as workshop information.
    - User Services and ILL Enhancement Regional Meeting Folders, April-August 1995 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Four VIVA folders from regional meetings, two from the User Services and two from the ILL Enhancement committees. Material included in the folders are draft brochures, meeting evaluations, attendance lists, meeting agendas, contact lists, information about the VIVA listserv and home page, VIVA fact sheets, ARIEL information,
  - Subseries 2.2: Trainings, Forums, and Workshops, April 1995-August 2001
    This subseries contains material generated by VIVA trainings, forums, and workshops held at institutions throughout Virginia. Material includes information about software and computer programs, registration and attendance information, group lists, information about electronic resources, contact lists and directories, meeting agendas, minutes and notes, fact sheets, VIVA packets, copyright information, VIVA Listserv and home page information, VIVA publications, fact sheets, travel reimbursement information, evaluations, ILL guidelines and lending reports.
    - ILL Workshops, April-July 1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Documents from an interlibrary loan workshop at George Mason University. Material includes Ariel information, attendance lists, contact directories, meeting agendas and notes, fact sheets, VIVA listserv and home page information and registration information.
    - August 1996 Workshops, May-August 1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Documents and correspondence from interlibrary loan workshops. Material includes shipping receipts, VIVA listserv and home page information and meeting agendas, minutes and notes.
    - Ariel Workshop, March-April 1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Documents and correspondence from Ariel workshop held on April 25 and 26, 1996. Material includes a training session proposal and tax information.
    - ILL Workshops, February-April 1996 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Documents and correspondence from Interlibrary Loan Workshops held on April 1 and 2, 1996 at VCU. Material includes evaluations, meeting agendas and minutes, participant lists, workshop descriptions.
    - ILL Meeting, January-February 1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Documents and correspondence from an Interlibrary Loan Meeting held on February 7, 1997. Material includes meeting notes, ILL guidelines and lending reports and a list of loaning libraries.
    - ILL Community Forum, September 1995-July 2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Documents and correspondence from an Interlibrary Loan Community Forum held on January 11, 2000 at UVA. Material includes a list of issues and concerns, group lists, registration and participant lists, contact lists, meeting agendas, notes, Lending information, evaluation forms, forum report and recommendations, also included are agendas from the July 14, 2000 ILL Community Forum.
    - ILL Community Forum, September 1995-January 2000 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Documents from an Interlibrary Loan Community Forum held on January 11, 2000 at UVA. Material includes three VIVA packets which contain VIVA publications, fact sheets, communication and travel reimbursement information, forum agendas, evaluation forms, ILL guidelines and information, group information, Ariel memos and lending information.
    - ILL Community Forum, July 2000-June 2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Documents and correspondence from an Interlibrary Loan Community Forum held on June 29, 2001 at UVA. Material includes ILL guidelines, copyright information, VIVA listserv and home page information, travel reimbursement information, evaluation forms, attendance lists, meeting notes and comment forms.
    - IAC Training User Services, May 3, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      A summary of attendees to the IAC database training session with evaluations. The training sessions were held throughout Virginia between March 22 and 28, 1996.
    - IAC Training Sessions, January 1997-February 1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Correspondence about an IAC database training session. Topics include registration, electronic resources and listserv and homepage information.
    - CIA-TF Forum on Access to Electronic Journals, January 2000 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Documents and correspondence from Task Force on Cataloging and Intellectual Access Forum on Access to Electronic Journals. Materials include two VIVA packets which contain VIVA publications, fact sheets, communication information, forum agendas, evaluation forms, presentation slides and travel reimbursement information. Also included are completed evaluation forms.
    - Training Fair, March-April 2000 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Documents and correspondence from a VIVA training fair. Materials include a VIVA packet which contains a VIVA publication, fact sheet, travel reimbursement information, fair agenda and an evaluation. Also included is a number of thank you letters thanking people for their assistance at the training fairs.
    - Training Fair, May-August 2001 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Documents and correspondence from a VIVA training fair. Materials include two VIVA packets which contains VIVA publications, listserv and home page information fact sheet, travel reimbursement information, fair agendas, evaluations, registration lists and electronic resource descriptions. Also included is directions to Blue Ridge Community College and registration information.
    - Event Information Folders, June 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Three VIVA information folders from the June 2001 ILL Community Forum. Material included in the folders is VIVA fact sheets, VIVA pamphlets, a forum schedule, ILL guidelines, copyright information, attendance lists, VIVA listserv and homepage information, travel reimbursement information and evaluation forms.
    - Public Institutions, October-November 1998 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Documents and correspondence from and for VIVA participants in the Dow Jones Training session who belong to public institutions. Material includes, travel reimbursement information, notes, a training session announcement and a memo about supplies for VIVA workshops.
    - Guide Folders, August 1999-March 2000 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Four VIVA information folders from training workshops. Material included in the folders are VIVA fact sheets, VIVA pamphlets, agendas for "Train the Trainer" Workshop for OVID Technologies, evaluation forms, travel reimbursement information, agendas for a VIVA training fair, campus and building maps and lists of training links.
    - VIVA Information Packets, September 1996-May 1997 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Two VIVA information folders from the "VIVA: Poised for the 21st Century" retreat. Material included in the folders are lists of VIVA committees and their members, travel reimbursement information, Kathy Perry's business card, retreat agendas, VIVA fact sheets, cost savings and value added survey executive summaries and executive summaries of the State Council of Higher Education in Virginia Library Advisory Committee Biennial Budget Proposal.
    - Coordinated Collection Management Workshop, November 1995-November 1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Documents and correspondence from the Coordinated Collection Management workshop. Material includes two articles by George Soete, workshop objective lists, workshop agendas and notes, a hotel contract, presentation slides and a workshop information packet.
    - George Soete Collaborative Collections Management Project, November 1995-January 1996 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Documents and correspondence from and about George Soete who was hired as a consultant and facilitated a retreat of the Collaborative Collections Management Projects and the joint session with the VIVA Steering Committee on November 21-23, 1996. Material includes notes from the workshop, University of California Shared Collections and Access Program information, articles by George Soete, a problem assessment worksheet, attendance information and collaborative collections management retreat notes.
- Series 3: VIVA Contact Directories, January 1995-September 2000; (2 boxes)
  This series contains information generated by VIVA contact directories.
  - January and March 1995 Contacts Directories, January-March 1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    The January and March 1995 contacts directories. Material includes correspondence and the January and March 1995 contacts directories. Also included in the January directory is access information, personnel information, hours and borrowing information for some of the member institution libraries.
  - January 1996 Contacts Directory (Box 17, Folder 2)
    The January 1996 contacts directory. Material includes VIVA committee lists and two copies of the January 1996 contacts directory.
  - January 1996 Contacts Directory Rough Draft, January 1996-January 1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Rough drafts of the VIVA contacts directory, with corrections written on almost every page. Material includes correspondence, faxes sent into George Mason University from VIVA member institutions with corrections, 757 area code information, committee lists and a Virginia Community College System Learning Resources Personnel Directory.
  - October 1996 Contacts Directory, May 1996-March 1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Documents and correspondence from and about the October 1996 contacts directory. Material includes a map of participating VIVA institutions, committee lists, notes and the October 1996 VIVA contacts directory.
  - March 1997 Contacts Directory, June 1996-March 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Documents and correspondence from and about the March 1997 contacts directory. Material includes committee lists, a memo about maintaining contact directories, VIVA fact sheets, and an incomplete copy of the March 1997 contacts directory.
  - March 1997 Contacts Directory II, June 1996-March 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Documents from and about the March 1997 contacts directory. Material includes committee lists, two copies of the March 1997 contacts directory, recommendations for organization structure and VIVA publications.
  - March 1998 Contacts Directory I, January-March 1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    The March 1998 contacts directory. Material includes a memo about maintaining contact directories, VIVA committee lists and two copies of the March 1998 contacts directory.
  - March 1998 Contacts Directory II, March 1998-July 1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Documents from and about the March 1998 contacts directory. Material includes correspondence, the March 1998 contacts directory and committee lists.
  - September 2000 Contacts Directory, June-September 2000 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Documents from and about the September 2000 contacts directory. Material includes correspondence, a response list, the September 2000 contacts directory and committee lists.
  - Contact Lists, January-April 1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Documents and correspondence from the compilation of the VIVA contact directories. Material is primarily fax and email correspondence but also includes guidelines for required contact information, a list of school's .pub extensions and budget information.
  - Committee Lists, September 1996-March 1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Listing of committee members from the Steering Committee, Collections Committee, Coordinated Collection Management Allied Health and Nursing Subcommittee, Coordinated Collection Management Business Subcommittee, Coordinated Collection Management Science and Technology Materials Subcommittee, ILL Enhancements Committee, Publicity Committee, Special Collections Committee, Technical Issues Committee and User Services Committee.
- Series 4: Cost Saving and Value Added Survey, July 1994-July 1999; (1.5 boxes)
  This series contains information generated by the cost saving and value added survey. The CSVA survey was sent to VIVA member institutions "to assess the impact of VIVA's shared purchase of electronic resources".
  - Cost Saving Survey 96-97, July 1994-March 1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes CSVA survey executive summaries from 95/96 and 96/97, rough drafts and corrections of CSVA information, financial benefit information, notes, budget information, questionnaire responses, narrative summaries and CSVA documents on 2 three and a half inch floppy disks.
  - Cost Saving Survey Final Draft, September-October 1997 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes the "final version" of the cost survey on 2 three and a half inch floppy disks, notes, rough drafts of the CSVA survey letter, a blank cost savings and value added survey, lists of journals available from Project Muse, lists of journals available from IAC, a list of journals available from Ideal (Academic Press), IAC Database subscription prices and Quattro Pro on a three and a half inch floppy disk and a three and a half inch floppy disk titled Cost Savings and Value Added Survey 1995-96 Original Documents.
  - Cost Savings Survey, June 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes a rough draft of the CSVA survey, a sample of the letter of instruction for the survey, a blank survey, IAC Database subscription prices and Quattro Pro on a three and a half inch floppy disk, a list of journals available from IAC, four three and a half inch floppy disks titled: FT-IAC.WQ1, IAC Databases Subscription Prices Quattro Pro, Charts.VIV in WP 5.1 and IASTitle.1ST UVA (VIVA) ? 6/21/96 as well as draft correspondence about the CSVA survey with edits.
  - Cost Savings and Value Added Survey Report, November 1996-April 1997 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes a portion of the VIVA Contacts Directory, a list of VIVA Institutions, a Cost Survey Report on a three and a half inch floppy disk, the Cost Savings Value Added Survey Report, a rough draft of the survey report with edits, a financial benefits report and the results of the survey.
  - Cost Savings and Value Added Survey, September 1996-July 1999 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes information about the VIVA listserv and home page, contact directory index, budget allocation information, VIVA fact sheet, VIVA electronic resources spreadsheets, a list of VIVA participating institutions, a financial benefits report, budget information, a rough draft of the State Council of Higher Education in Virginia Library Advisory Committee 1998-2000 Biennial Budget Proposal, survey results, a lists of participating institutions, a narrative for the survey and completed surveys from J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College, Averett College, Bridgewater College, Emory and Henry College and Ferrum College.
  - Cost Savings and Value Added Survey, September 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Documents and correspondence from the 1996-1997 cost savings and value added survey. Material includes instructions for filling out the CSVA survey, a blank survey and a list of journals available from project muse.
  - Miscellaneous Cost Savings Value and Added Survey Documents, January 1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Miscellaneous documents from the cost savings and value added survey. Material includes a CSVA survey narrative and rough drafts of the results of the CSVA survey and two three and a half inch floppy disks with subscription prices worksheets.
  - Completed Cost Savings and Value Added Surveys, June-October 1996 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Completed cost savings and value added surveys from the following institutions (organized alphabetically): Blue Ridge Community College, Central Virginia Community College, Christopher Newport University, Clinch Valley College, Dabney S. Lancaster Community College, Danville Community College, Eastern Shore Community College, George Mason University, Hampden-Sydney College, Hollins College, J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College, James Madison University, John Tyler Community College, Liberty University, Longwood College, Lord Fairfax Community College, Lynchburg College, Mary Baldwin College, Mary Washington College, Marymount University, Mountain Empire Community College, Norfolk State University, Northern Virginia Community College Alexandria Campus, Northern Virginia Community College Manassas Campus, Old Dominion University, Piedmont Virginia Community College, Radford University, Randolph-Macon Women's College, Rapphannock Community College, Regent University, Richard Bland College, University of Richmond, Roanoke College, Southside Virginia Community College, Sweet Briar College, Thomas Nelson Community College, Tidewater Community College at Chesapeake Campus, Tidewater Community College at Portsmouth Campus, Tidewater Community College Virginia Beach Campus, University of Virginia, University of Virginia Business School, University of Virginia Law School, Virginia Commonwealth University, Virginia Highlands Community College, Virginia Military Institute, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Virginia Union University, Virginia Western Community College, Washington and Lee University, Washington and Lee University Law School, College of William and Mary, College of William and Mary Law School and Wytheville Community College. Also included is instructions for filling out the survey and a completed IAC Databases Full-Text Journals List Worksheet from Virginia Union.
  - VIVA-Cost Savings and Value Added Survey, June 1996-November 1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Documents and correspondence from the cost savings and value added survey. Material include instructional letters, a blank survey, a list of journals available from IAC Databases and Project Muse, survey distribution checklists, survey planning subcommittee correspondence, notes and financial benefit lists.
- Series 5: Miscellaneous Documents, November 1994-January 2003; (0.5 box)
  This series contains miscellaneous and unfiled documents generated by the Virtual Library of Virginia.